Nakeshia L. Lorde B.Sc. BSEE

1st Avenue Clover Crescent, Prior Park, St. James Phone: (246) 236 - 3949

Email: lordenakeshia@gmail.com https://nakeshialorde.github.io/nllprofile/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/nakeshia-lorde-ab7391144/

PROFILE

Electrical Engineer with several years experience and proven technical skills in trouble-shooting electrical and instrumentation equipment, and designing electrical layouts using NEC code. Competent in the drafting of project life cycles and initiating engineering processes, software life-cycle, enhancing existing product performance, exceptional mathematical and science skills, the ability to understand technical diagrams and experience working with engineering design software such as AutoCAD and Matlab. Excellent communication, analytical, report writing and decision making skills.

EDUCATION

Alabama Agricultural and Mechanical University (Normal, Al) December 11th 2015

Bachelors of Science in Electrical Engineering (Concentration Computer Engineering) Honors

Relevant coursework: • Software Engineering• Operating Systems • Data Structures • • Microprocessors • Numerical Methods

Organizations and Associations: Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE)• National Society of Black Engineers(NSBE) • International Student Association • Barbados Association of Professional Engineers.

SKILLS

Hardware: Analog Discovery Kit • Agilent 34401A 6.5 Digital Multimeter• Agilent E3630A Triple-Output DC Power Supply• Agilent 33220A 20MHz Function/Arbitrary Waveform Generator• TDS 2024B Four Channel Digital Storage Oscilloscope 200 MHz 2GS/s• AFG 3021 Tektronix Single Channel Function Generator• NI ELVIS I&NI ELVIS II• TLA502 Tektronix Logic Analyzer.

Software: Microsoft Office Suite (Word, Excel, Project, PowerPoint) • Outlook • Microsoft Visual Studio • Matlab • National Instruments Lab VIEW • Texas Execute and Simulate Microcomputer Simulator • Freescale Code Warrior IDE • NI Multisim• Xilinx ISE ISim• AutoCAD.

Programming Languages: C#, Go, C++, Node.js

The University of the West Indies (Cave Hill Campus) September 31st 2009

Bachelors of Science (Double Major) Sociology and Law - Honors

Relevant Coursework: Qualitative Research Methods • Survey and Design Analysis • Techniques of Investigation • Methodology • Commonwealth Caribbean Human Rights • Constitutional Law • Survey Design and Analysis • Employment Law • Equitable Remedies • Law and Legal Systems • Public International Law I&II • Real Property I & II • Family Law II • International Law of Human Rights • Administration of Trusts and Estates • Criminal Law I.

Barbados Community College July 31st 2006

Associate Degree in Arts (Double Major) Sociology and History - Honors

Relevant Coursework: English and Communication • Introduction to Management • Computer Awareness • Social Institutions • Social Change • Techniques of Investigation • Methodology • Practical Mathematics • Sociological Perspective.

Caribbean Examination Council - General

- English A Grade I
- History Grade I
- Information Technology Grade I
- Office Procedures Grade I
- Social Studies Grade II
- Geography Grade III
- Principles of Business Grade III

WORK EXPERIENCE

Hyuna International (Hastings, Christ Church)

Back-End Web Developer (Temporary) October 2016-January 2017

- Responsible for the development and programming of various systems and databases related to the publication, maintenance, and tracking of corporate-wide web-based assets.
- Analyzing PHP code and derive business rules;
- Diagnose and quickly find faulty code and write fixes (code in PHP);
- Reliably write features in PHP code in a timely manner with minimum supervision and support;
- Work with GIT using GIT flow and do tasks such as reverting merges, and cherry-picking;
- Document an end user's requirements and technical details, and identify parts of the existing code base to be updated;
- Document and demonstrate solutions by developing documentation, flowcharts, layouts, diagrams, charts, code comments and clear code;
- Take part in task planning, task estimation and code reviews;
- Write Unit Tests and practice TDD;
- Write complex SQL queries, using nesting;
- Construct a database table based on user's requirements following ACID principles.

- Hyuna International is an online media distribution business that owns and operates subscriber based multimedia content platforms.
- These platforms distribute digital content such as movies, music, games and e-books. It is worldwide service, and the Company has affiliate companies in Canada, Europe and the United States.

Alabama Agricultural and Mechanical University (Department of Electrical Engineering) Lab Assistant

August 2013 – December 2015

- Assisted with the introduction and integration of the Analog Discovery Kit into the Lab for Sophomore students.
- Setup Analog Discovery Kit for various experiments.

Taylor Optimum Intellect Summer Internship

May 2013 – August 2013, May 2014 – August 2014, May 2015 – August 2015 Huntsville, Alabama

- Enhanced existing product performance in coordination with development teams.
- Drafted project life cycles to assist other departments as required.
- Initiated engineering processes for design preparation.
- Participated in all development process activities.
- Testing software to ensure the code is correct debugged errors.
- Familiar with the software development life-cycle.

Alabama Agricultural and Mechanical University (Huntsville, Alabama)

Student Assistant

January 2012 – May 2013

- Maintain scheduled office hours and assist with the daily office operation as determined by supervisor.
- Type correspondence, entering data/computing.
- Answer phones
- Filing
- Run errands for Campus Life Staff

Barbados Youth Business Trust (Bridgetown, Barbados) January 2010-December 2010 **Project Assistant** – IDB Mentoring Model to Develop Young Entrepreneurs

- Responsible for the administrative support of the project
- Assist with the planning, designing and printing of mentors and entrepreneurs' literature
- Make logistical arrangements for the organization of meetings and trainings for potential mentors and entrepreneurs
- Coordinate the development of a sustainable network and dissemination of the results newsletters and case studies.
- Assist project management in performing budget cycle

- Assist the project team in drafting project progress reports
- Prepared events manual and created mentor's database
- Organized entrepreneurs filing systems and conducted site visits

Mount Gay Distilleries Limited – (Spring Garden, Barbados) July 2009 – September 2009 **Temporary Assistant to Brand Managers**

- Researched brand information
- Assisted in the organization of brand showcase
- Made follow up calls for events
- Typed and mailed invitations for events

Ministry of Education - Underachievers Summer School May 2007 - August 2007 **Teaching Assistant**

- Taught Social Studies to students between the ages of 11 years 16 years.
- Organized teaching plan and activities to follow syllabus.
- Organized progress test and evaluations of lessons plans

Systems Consulting Limited January 2007 - May 2007 **Telephone Service Representative**

- Conducted telephone surveys
- Followed up with clients

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Dean's List2012-2015
- Honor Roll 2012-2015

INTERESTS

Volunteering • Keeping updated with Programming • Learning Application Development (IOS-Swift) • Writing/Poetry • Front End Web Design: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and Jquery, Circuit Projects.

REFERENCES

Available on Request